[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Shadow Punisher]
[Divine Constable Tally]
[Episode 17]
I guess
Xuanyuan Shan will eventually find out
that it was me who told
the Crown Prince about the government salt.
I bet
she'll probably come looking for trouble.
Who does Xuanyuan Shan think she is?
No need to wait any longer.
Let's settle the score right now.
Chief Xuanyuan.
I was just talking nonsense.
Please don't take it to heart.
Thank you, Chief Xuanyuan.
I'll take my leave now.
Li Qingyang,
I can't protect you.
You're on your own.
The Mingling case involves the royal family.
It should have been investigated thoroughly
before it was submitted to His Majesty.
Li Qingyang,
you actually handed over the case evidence
to the Crown Prince privately.
Do you know what a huge trouble you've caused?
If a prince breaks the law, he gets the same penalty as the commoners.
The evidence of the Mingling case is conclusive.
The First Prince deserves it.
Whether His Majesty learned of it
sooner or later—
what difference does it make?
Go on.
If this case
was submitted by the Divine Constable Bureau,
I think
His Majesty, to balance the power in the court,
would definitely protect the First Prince once.
So,
it's better to leak this news
to the Crown Prince
and let him take the lead.
This way,
not only is the First Prince punished,
but it also clears the relationship
with the Divine Constable Bureau.
Chief Xuanyuan.,
actually, I am just
solving problems for you.
Chief Xuanyuan,
there is one more thing
I still can't figure out.
Before His Majesty issued an edict
to punish the First Prince,
the government salt matter
had already spread among the people.
I once sent people
to secretly investigate the source of the news,
but could never track it down.
You mean
besides you,
someone else leaked the news?
I think
this person must hope
to cause chaos in the Great Shi's court.
Isn't that
the same as you?
I wouldn't dare.
Think about it. The government salt matter
is known to only a few people.
I guess
this person either has been
following us from the start,
or
he is from the Divine Constable Bureau.
I see.
If there's anything else, just say it all at once.
There is indeed one more thing I want to ask of you.
[Winter's Haven]
How did it go? What did the Chief say?
After much persuasion,
she finally agreed
to let Xia Jiuying stay.
However,
the Chief has her own arrangements.
That's good.
At least she has
a place to stay.
Our trip to Mingling this time
can be considered an unexpected gain.
The Dark Night Organization
wanted to kill Jiuying to silence her
because they were afraid she would
reveal the location of the cave,
thereby exposing
their mutation of the demon wolves.
Having demon-men isn't enough.
They want to cultivate more monsters.
I'm worried that next,
Liluo will make a major move.
Right.
Our division must be
on high alert these next few days.
The details of the Mingling case,
from beginning to end,
are known only to the Divine Constable Bureau.
I didn't expect
you to know it so clearly.
Everything I do
is for the Holy Lord.
The Great Shi Dynasty must be thrown into chaos.
The more chaotic it is,
the more advantageous it is for us.
In this Tianhuang City,
when it comes to being well-informed,
no one can compare to Li Qingyang.
If you spread news privately,
aren't you afraid
he will suspect you?
What do I have to be afraid of?
His life
is in my hands.
[Tianshu Pavilion]
Has the God of Lies, Qipi,
also turned to dust?
Chief.
I called you here
to let you meet someone.
Who?
Jiuying?
I initially wanted to arrange a place for her,
but after spending a few days with her,
I found she is agile and quick-witted.
She's good material for a constable.
I'll keep her in the division and teach her myself,
starting as a trainee constable.
I have to say,
Jiuying looks quite good in this outfit.
It's great that she can stay.
Quick, thank the Chief.
Thank you, Chief.
Oh no. It's the Tianshu Pavilion.
A Liluo man?
To think you can come and go freely
in the Tianshu Pavilion.
[Tianshu Pavilion]
Who exactly are you?
Unless he's from the Divine Constable Bureau.
Just like Lou Tianming,
he's a mole planted
by Liluo in the Divine Constable Bureau.
I don't care who he is.
Let's capture him first!
Stop!
Let him go.
Chief, he's from Liluo.
He is extremely audacious.
He trespassed into the Tianshu Pavilion.
I don't need to explain to you.
What happened at the Tianshu Pavilion today
must not be revealed to anyone.
Otherwise, you will be severely punished.
Did you hear me?
-Yes. -Yes.
What's going on?
If word gets out
that I came to see you tonight...
Just do your job.
No one in the Divine Constable Bureau
will stand in your way.
Now that the First Prince has lost power,
there's an undercurrent at court.
It is a time of change.
Chief, don't miss this chance.
Such lightness skill
is truly incredible.
Don't worry.
I know who that kid is.
I'll handle him.
[Star-Gathering Pavilion]
Master.
Ask the girls to work a little harder
and find someone for me.
Please tell me, Master.
He's a middle-aged man
with rather delicate features.
He's not actually that old,
just unkempt,
so he looks older than he is.
His martial arts are not weak either.
I want to know all his movements
after he entered Tianhuang City.
Yes.
The girls have checked all the martial artists
going in and out of
Tianhuang City.
There really aren't many experts
who match your description:
a square face, small eyes,
looks old but is actually
middle-aged.
Although most of them have no fixed residence,
they all have names in jianghu.
Only one among them stands out—
his identity is mysterious, and his background unknown.
But he has been living in the same place
for several days in a row.
Where?
Lanyue Pavilion.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Everyone,
former Minister of Works, Tang Yiming,
Master Tang,
was the best craftsman in the world before he entered the government.
He was an expert
in mechanics and landscaping.
He was known as the reincarnation of Lu Ban.
After resigning,
he spent 5 years drawing blueprints.
He and his son, Tang Wei,
spent six years
[Lanyue Pavilion]
building the number one pavilion in the Great Shi.
Counting the days,
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Lanyue Pavilion has been built for ten years.
From the top, you can see all the scenery of Tianhuang City.
It's said that
you can even see the imperial palace clearly.
Before the construction of Lanyue Pavilion,
an imperial censor once submitted a memorial,
arguing that a hundred-foot tower towering above the palace
was a great act of disrespect.
Yes.
Indeed.
How could it be taller than the palace?
But our wise His Majesty
[Lanyue Pavilion]
didn't care.
He even wrote 8 big characters.
Which 8 characters?
Yes, tell us.
Harmony between ruler and subject—
what's wrong with that?
What... What does this mean?
-And then? -And then?
-Yes, what happened next? -And then?
Keep going.
Tell us.
If you want to know what happened next,
listen to the next chapter.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Zhenzhu.
Li Si?
Why are you here?
Every early autumn,
naturally,
[Lanyue Pavilion]
the lantern festival at Lanyue Pavilion
is the liveliest.
How could I miss it?
Let me help you.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Just now,
what did you wish for?
I wished for the Great Shi Dynasty to have
peace in the world and prosperity for the people.
A good wish.
Since we're here,
why don't
we stroll around Lanyue Pavilion?
How about that?
Let's go.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
This Lanyue Pavilion
is a business from 10 years ago.
It's too formal
and lacks novelty,
so its foot traffic
is naturally less than Star-Gathering Pavilion.
I wonder if you've heard
a strange tale.
The boss of Lanyue Pavilion is Tang Wei,
and he has quite a background.
His father
was the former Minister of Works.
He resigned years ago to seek the Dao.
It's said he was enlightened
and ascended to become an immortal.
An old servant saw with his own eyes
a mechanical wooden bird
circling a rainbow
and carrying Master Tang's body to the sky.
This alarmed His Majesty
and the Chief.
Unfortunately, the Divine Constable Bureau searched for days
but found neither Master Tang's body
nor
the wreckage of the wooden bird.
A mechanical wooden bird?
Could Master Tang
be the reincarnation of Lu Ban?
I have never believed
in ghosts and gods.
Young Master Qingyang,
you are right.
My master indeed attained immortality.
You are?
[Qin Dayuan, Butler of Tang Manor]
The butler of the Tang residence— Qin Dayuan.
You recognize me?
My young master ordered me to be here
to wait for you.
Please.
Butler Qin,
how did Young Master Tang know
I would come to visit?
My young master calculated
that you would come on his birthday.
Over the years, the young master
has never miscalculated.
I don't believe in ghosts or gods,
nor do I believe in divination or prophecies.
Young Master Qingyang relies on being
[Shuyue Residence]
the Crown Prince's favorite
to slander gods and immortals here.
You should know that
when I served the Crown Prince,
he wasn't even born yet.
Such a mortal with no connection to immortals,
why bother with him?
It's better to drink elixirs in the forest
and retreat to the mountains.
No, no, no.
[Shuyue Residence]
Retreating to the deep mountains
cannot isolate me from the secular world.
Why not go and return?
Who are these two?
These are
some of the young master's friends.
You don't need to pay them any mind.
It doesn't matter.
[Shuyue Residence]
The young master has been waiting on the seventh floor
for a long time.
Please, Master.
Thank you.
[Sixth Floor]
You must be Tang Wei, Boss Tang?
Today is your birthday.
I came in a hurry
and didn't prepare a gift.
The day of arrival is the day of departure.
What is there to rejoice in arriving,
and what is there to grieve in departing?
With neither grief nor joy,
why prepare a gift?
My words were inappropriate;
please forgive me.
I lack spiritual insight.
However,
from what you're saying,
your birthday
is about to become your death anniversary.
A few days ago,
my father appeared in a dream from the heavenly realm,
saying,
the day of arrival is the day of departure.
He prophesied that on my birthday,
I would pass on to the heavenly realm.
Boss Tang,
midnight is approaching.
But looking at you,
aren't you perfectly fine?
[Tang Wei]
Beautiful moonlight, beautiful night.
How about enjoying it with me, Young Master Qingyang?
If it's truly as you say,
and your days are numbered,
you should spend them with your family.
I am neither family nor friend.
It seems quite inconvenient.
Young Master Qingyang and I
are both people who cannot see our past clearly.
That's why I say
we are fated to meet.
What do you mean by not seeing the past clearly?
Since it cannot be seen clearly,
how can it be explained clearly?
Back to the point.
Butler Qin said
you've been waiting for me here for a long time.
I wonder,
what advice do you have, Boss Tang?
I have something to give you.
I can't accept a reward without merit.
What if I say this item
is related to Liluo?
Did you see Boss Tang?
What did you talk about
for so long?
[Lanyue Pavilion]
This Lanyue Pavilion is connected to Liluo.
Why do you say that?
This was given to me by Boss Tang.
He said...
This item is related to Liluo.
I still don't know
what this really is,
and
what Boss Tang's purpose
in giving it to me
really is.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Something happened!
Someone fell from above!
Young Master!
Boss Tang.
[Lanyue Pavilion Ascension Case]
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Keep an eye on everything.
How is it?
Skull, sternum, and leg bones
have multiple fractures.
The cause of death is falling from a height.
I just don't know if he fell on his own
or was pushed.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
As for the footprints in the room,
besides Tang Wei, Qin Dayuan,
and Li Si's,
there's a fourth one.
What are you thinking about?
There are three people
who need to be watched immediately.
Qin Dayuan and
the two guests in the sixth-floor private room.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
People down there, step back!
Step back, everyone.
Step back.
Everyone, step back.
Okay.
Step back.
The position is a bit far.
The position is a bit far!
Look.
If he was pushed down,
the landing position
would be further
than if he jumped himself.
This doesn't count as me pushing him.
The premise of it being further
is that the victim resisted desperately,
and the killer had to use
a lot of force.
Okay, wait here.
Give it to me.
Make way!
Just now it landed on its face,
this time on its back.
Yes.
No matter how determined to die,
people who commit suicide
always look at the ground,
usually face down.
But if they are pushed,
the landing part is uncertain.
And also,
suicide victims usually have a peaceful face.
But if they struggled desperately
and were pushed,
their face would be grim.
Li Si said
Tang Wei had already predicted
that he would die today.
So,
he might not have struggled desperately.
Zhenzhu, careful!
There's a problem with this railing.
It can't bear any weight at all.
In that case,
if Boss Tang
didn't know there was a problem with the railing
and leaned against it
to enjoy the moon as usual,
then he would fall down
without anyone pushing him.
No wonder we couldn't tell from the body
whether he was pushed
or fell down himself.
Do you think this railing
is in disrepair
or...
Man-made.
This tenon
was obviously
unscrewed on purpose,
not due to
weathering.
Lanyue Pavilion has regular maintenance.
If such a big mistake was found,
it wouldn't be ignored.
The person in charge of maintenance
seems to be Qin Dayuan.
This person can be investigated.
My lords,
Constable Qingyang has already taken Qin Dayuan
to the Divine Constable Bureau.
And before the incident,
the two guests on the sixth floor,
Lord Huang Gang
and Lord Jiang Zeshui,
were also taken back
by Constable Qingyang.
Li Si acts fast.
Is there anyone else on the sixth floor
who can be taken back for interrogation?
No, Mr. Yan.
We both
have confirmed it.
The sixth floor tonight
was booked by the two lords.
No one else has come up.
To go up and down Lanyue Pavilion,
you must pass through the stairs.
To get to the seventh floor,
you must go up floor by floor.
So,
if there's a suspect,
it's most likely the two of them.
Young Master Qingyang interrogated me last night.
Lanyue Pavilion has regular maintenance,
which I personally supervise.
So it's impossible
for the railing to be unsteady.
What if you have a problem?
Back then, I was
just a low-level servant in the Tang Mansion,
bullied by others.
Thanks to the Master and Young Master
for protecting me many times,
and promoting me to butler.
I must repay this favor.
My death is not a pity,
but I beg you to find the murderer
to avenge the Young Master.
Steward Qin, get up first.
His pulse shows
palpitations caused by anger,
not panic.
He's not lying.
Since Li Si interrogated him,
he's probably fine.
It all depends on the two on the sixth floor.
The Crown Prince had a severe illness in his childhood.
His body was too weak to absorb tonics.
It was our master
who, relying on a bowl
of porridge that nourished qi and blood,
[Former Head of the Imperial Kitchen, Huang Gang]
helped the Crown Prince survive.
Come to think of it, our master
has served two emperors
and one Crown Prince.
Even if Xuanyuan Shan came,
he wouldn't dare to interrogate our master.
Who are you two to question him?
Our Lord Jiang has managed water systems countless times.
He is known as Yu the Great reborn.
When the current His Majesty was still a prince,
[Former River Supervisor, Jiang Zeshui]
it was with the help of
our master
that the dikes on both sides of the Yellow River were built,
saving countless lives.
Have you lost your minds
to dare question him?
Why don't you call that
Xuanyuan Shan out
to give our master
a face-to-face apology?
Get out!
Master!
Take him away!
-Master. -Master.
The Divine Constable Bureau answers directly to imperial power.
No matter what his status is.
Those two lackeys
have already been kicked out by me.
If you two lords don't say anything,
I can completely use torture.
Whatever the consequences,
I will bear them alone.
Are you hard of hearing?
Can't you hear me?
Brother Sanhuo.
Your upright and unyielding character
truly makes me admire you.
But even if you aren't afraid,
look at them.
With the age of these two elders,
let alone severe torture,
even staying in jail for a few days,
I'm afraid
they might pass away at any moment.
From what you mean,
not only can we not touch them,
but we also have to worship them.
That's not necessary either—
no need to make it that troublesome.
Release Lord Jiang and Lord Huang!
Why arrest
Lord Jiang and Lord Huang?
What evidence do you have?
I think
these two elders in the Divine Constable Bureau
won't stay for long.
Release Lord Jiang!
[Divine Constable Bureau]
Why arrest
Lord Jiang and Lord Huang?
What evidence do you have?
[Divine Constable Bureau]
Release them now!
I'll count to three.
If you don't disperse,
the cells in the back courtyard of the Divine Constable Bureau
are waiting for you.
Meng, who are you trying to scare?
That's right!
Right!
One.
Don't be afraid, everyone.
Lord Jiang and Lord Huang
have always treated us well!
-Even if we risk our lives today... -That's right!
Two!
we have to save them!
Release Lord Jiang and Lord Huang!
Mr. Meng!
Mr. Meng, please stop!
[Divine Constable Bureau]
Constable Ghost, stop playing.
Don't hurt Lord Huang
and Lord Jiang.
Are you two eunuchs
representing His Majesty and the Eastern Palace
to plead for mercy?
Lady Xuanyuan.
If His Majesty issues an edict,
I will naturally release them.
Well...
Lady Xuanyuan,
how could His Majesty issue an explicit decree
to interfere with the Divine Constable Bureau's handling of a case?
His Majesty is wise.
You...
You naturally understand
His Majesty's intention.
Why pretend to be confused?
The two elders are old,
and it's not suitable to torture them.
Our Divine Constable Bureau will treat them well.
Lady Xuanyuan means
the Divine Constable Bureau refuses to release them?
If I
release them because of their past status,
our Divine Constable Bureau will lose its prestige,
but His Majesty
will lose face too.
That's why
he didn't issue an explicit decree.
You two should know this.
I know.
Never mind, let's go back first.
Take care.
Dismissed. It's nothing.
How's the interrogation
[Pillar of the Realm]
with Li Si and Yan Cheng?
Strangely,
the two elders neither defend themselves
nor panic.
It seems they are
happy about something.
And according to the guy in Lanyue Pavilion,
they booked the private room on the 6th floor last night.
They neither sought beauties
nor invited friends.
Instead,
they were plotting something.
So,
we have to make them talk.
Since we can't torture them,
how should we interrogate them?
Please instruct.
Zhenzhu,
you interrogate them.
Trapped in the mortal world for 80 years,
my heart is like a Taiyi immortal in the water.
Going out with a smile, free of obstacles,
clouds in the West Lake, moon in the sky.
Pigs and sheep sit on the kang,
relatives are boiled in the pot.
Daughters eat their mothers' flesh,
sons beat their fathers' skin drums.
Relatives come to congratulate,
I think it's really bitter.
Uncles,
I am Bai Zhenzhu.
When I was young, I met you
at my house.
So you are the apple of the elder's eye.
You are indeed extraordinary.
Since we are on the same path,
we will tell you everything we know.
I have long heard
that Mr. Tang never miscalculates,
and I deeply admire him.
This time, I also want
to ask you two.
Did Mr. Tang really predict
his own death long ago?
Before my nephew passed away,
he once told us
that there would be imprisonment,
but it wouldn't be a big deal.
[To Lord Huang, Your Nephew Tang Wei]
Approaching the end, suddenly happy and sad.
Gloomy in prison, both safe and dangerous.
Nephew Tang Wei.
Autumn of the 37th year of Hongyun.
[With my final return drawing near, I am at once joyful and sorrowful. The prison is dark and dreary, where safety and danger walk hand in hand.]
So
Mr. Tang had already foreseen
that you two uncles
would be brought to the Divine Constable Bureau.
Can Tang Wei
really foresee the future?
[Lanyue Pavilion]
Thank you, Steward Qin.
According to your orders,
the private rooms of Lord Huang and Lord Jiang
remain untouched.
According to the previous
statement of the staff in the building,
there have always been only
two guests, Huang Gang and Jiang Zeshui, on this sixth floor.
But why are there four sets of bowls and chopsticks?
These are the affairs of the lords.
Servants like us
wouldn't know.
Steward Qin,
I want to ask you a question.
There was a middle-aged man
with excellent skills and a square face with narrow eyes.
This person stayed in this Lanyue Pavilion
for several days.
Do you have any impression?
In this Lanyue Pavilion,
with so many people coming and going every day,
I really can't remember.
What exactly does this thing
have to do with Liluo?
[Lanyue Pavilion]
These footprints...
No.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
There are so many carpets
laid in Lanyue Pavilion.
Walking all the way from the first floor to the seventh floor,
how could it be possible to leave
such a complete footprint?
Right.
No matter how dirty the shoes are,
they would have been wiped clean.
That footprint was left on purpose.
To leave a footprint like this,
you have to be like me
and step down hard.
If
the killer wanted to sneak up from behind,
how could they walk like this?
Therefore,
Tang Wei committed suicide.
He left this footprint
to create the illusion
that someone was behind him.
But Tang Wei was perfectly fine.
Why would he end his own life?
My lords.
We found this suicide note
left by Tang Wei
[Suicide Note]
in the account books
at the Lanyue Pavilion.
When did you find it?
About half an hour ago.
1 PM.
We just found out Tang Wei committed suicide,
and you guys found his suicide note
so quickly?
Writing this letter,
I am still a living person.
When you read this letter,
I will already be a ghost in the underworld.
Tang Wei wrote it elegantly.
But between the lines,
it reveals something bizarre.
Bizarre?
Tang Wei's parents are dead.
He has no wife or children.
He became a Taoist in recent years,
and doesn't have any close friends.
Then who is this
suicide note written to?
Moreover,
[Tang Wei's Note]
who does 'you' refer to?
How is it?
Judging from the handwriting,
Mr. Tang's writing
is agile and fast.
The strokes are thin but vigorous,
thin but not losing their flesh.
His large characters especially show
their graceful charm.
Come on.
Just tell me,
is it his or not?
The suicide note is indeed written by Mr. Tang.
Please.
It seems that
Boss Tang really might have
killed himself.
No wonder he could predict
that Lord Huang and Lord Jiang
would face imprisonment.
He staged it himself,
jumping down from Lanyue Pavilion.
He definitely figured out
that Huang and Jiang
would be taken away by our Divine Constable Bureau.
It seems
we need to inform
Qin Dayuan about this.